<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Industrial Strength DevOps</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Industrial Strength DevOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Sign Up for a FREE FOR LIFE Oracle Cloud Instance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/toolset-why-getting-free-oci-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/toolset-why-getting-free-oci-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-you-should-sign-up-for-a-free-for-life-oracle-cloud-instance&#34;&gt;Why You Should Sign Up for a FREE FOR LIFE Oracle Cloud Instance&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building hobby projects with AI pair programming (Copilot, ChatGPT, etc.) is exhilarating—but without a solid operations layer, your code can become fragile, unmaintainable, and vulnerable to “hallucinations.” Enter &lt;strong&gt;Oracle Cloud Always Free Tier&lt;/strong&gt;: a truly free-for-life cloud sandbox that gives you industrial-strength DevOps capabilities at zero cost. Below, we’ll explore why it’s worth your time, plus a few caveats to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I’m Writing a Series of Articles Directed at Home Coders: Industrial Strength DevOps at Home and for Free</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/toolset-why-am-i-doing-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/toolset-why-am-i-doing-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a passionate hobby coder, I’ve always been driven by curiosity—exploring new languages, frameworks, and approaches. With AI-powered pair programming tools like Copilot and friends, the excitement of seeing your ideas come to life has never been easier. But there’s a catch: turning those hobby projects into something resilient, maintainable, and production-grade requires more than just fancy code generation. It requires an operations mindset.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-am-i-writing-a-series-of-articles-directed-at-home-coders&#34;&gt;Why am I writing a series of articles directed at home coders?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I see a gap between what home coders often do and what’s needed to elevate those projects to the next level. Professional projects don’t just live and die by their codebase—they’re supported by a robust operations layer: CI/CD pipelines, infrastructure automation, security best practices, and monitoring. That’s where the real magic happens, and where hobby coders often get left behind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
